Andras Gyorgy

Curriculum Vitæ

NYU Abu Dhabi Office C1-159 ☑ andras.gyorgy@nyu.edu ☑ http://netb.io

Research Snapshot

My work lies at the interface of network dynamics and synthetic biology. In my research, I combine wetlab experiments with engineering and math (control theory, network science, statistics, optimization) to develop quantitative tools with particular emphasis on synthetic biology applications.

Employment

New York University Abu Dhabi, Assistant Professor of Electrical Engineering
 University of California, Berkeley, Postdoctoral Researcher with Murat Arcak

Education

2016 Massachusetts Institute of Technology

PhD in Electrical Engineering

Thesis: Functional modularity of gene networks

Advisor: Domitilla Del Vecchio

2011 Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Hungary MS in Biomedical Engineering

2009 Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Hungary MS in Electrical Engineering

Publications

Journal papers

- [1] A Gyorgy, M Arcak (2017) Pattern formation over multigraphs, *IEEE Transactions* on Network Science and Engineering (Accepted)
- [2] JW Lee, A Gyorgy, DE Cameron, N Pyenson, KR Choi, JC Way, PA Silver, D Del Vecchio, JJ Collins (2016) Creating single-copy genetic circuits, *Molecular Cell*, 63(2):329–336
- [3] A Gyorgy, JI Jimenez, J Yazbek, H Chung, R Weiss, D Del Vecchio (2015) Isocost lines describe the cellular economy of genetic circuits, *Biophysical Journal*, 109(3):639–646
- [4] A Gyorgy, D Del Vecchio (2014) Modular composition of gene transcription networks, *PLoS Computational Biology*, 10(3): e1003486
- [5] A Gyorgy, L Kovacs, P Szalay, DA Drexler, B Benyo, Z Benyo (2011) Quasi-model-based control of type 1 diabetes mellitus, Journal of Electrical and Computer Eng,

[6] L Kovacs, B Kulcsar, A Gyorgy, Z Benyo (2011) Robust servo control of a novel type 1 diabetic model, Optimal Control Application and Methods, John Wiley & Sons, 2:215–238

Conference papers

- [1] A Gyorgy, M Arcak (2017) Pattern formation over graphs with asymmetric connections, *IFAC World Congress*
- [2] A Gyorgy, RM Murray (2016) Quantifying resource competition and its effects in the TX-TL System, *IEEE Conference on Decision and Control*
- [3] TP Prescott, **A Gyorgy** (2015) Bounding the effect of retroactivity in the presence of parameter uncertainty, *IEEE American Control Conference*
- [4] A Gyorgy, D Del Vecchio (2014) Limitations and trade-offs in gene expression due to competition for shared cellular resources (invited paper), *IEEE Conference on Decision and Control*
- [5] A Gyorgy, D Del Vecchio (2013) How slaves affect a master module in gene transcription networks (invited paper), *IEEE Conference on Decision and Control*
- [6] A Gyorgy, D Del Vecchio (2012) Retroactivity to the input and Thevenin's theorem for complex gene transcription networks (invited paper), *IEEE Conference on Decision and Control*
- [7] L Kovacs, A Gyorgy, P Szalay, DA Drexler, B Benyo, Z Benyo (2011) Quasi model based optimal control of type 1 diabetes mellitus, *IFAC World Congress*
- [8] A Gyorgy, P Szalay, Z Benyo, B Benyo, A Kovacsa, L Kovacs (2010) ANFIS regulated type 1 diabetic model for different glucose absorption scenarios, *IEEE Conference on Intelligent Engineering Systems*
- [9] L Kovacs, **A Gyorgy**, B Kulcsar, P Szalay, B Benyo, Z Benyo (2010) Robust control of type 1 diabetes using μ -synthesis, *UKACC Conference on Control*
- [10] L Kovacs, A Gyorgy, P Szalay, B Benyo, Z Benyo, CE Hann, JG Chase (2010) Investigating the applicability of qALPV modeling to ICU models for glycaemic control, UKACC Conference on Control
- [11] A Gyorgy, I Harmati (2009) Motion planning algorithms for tactical actions in robot soccer, *IEEE European Control Conference*
- [11] L Kovacs, A Gyorgy, Zs Almassy, Z Benyo (2009) Analyzing a novel model of human blood glucose system at molecular levels, *IEEE European Control Conference*
- [12] L Kovacs, A Gyorgy, B Benyo (2009) Type 1 diabetes regulated by ANFIS at molecular levels, World Congress on Medical Physics and Biomedical Engineering
- [13] A Gyorgy, T Barbarics, Zs Puspoki, J Padanyi (2009) Application of neural networks in mine detection, *International Conference on Climbing and Walking Robots and the Support Technologies for Mobile Machines*

Talks

2015 Foundations of Systems Biology in Engineering, Boston, MA

A systems-level approach to characterize context-dependence in biomolecular networks

2014 Winter q-bio Meeting, Maui, HI

Dynamics of complex gene transcription networks

2013 Design Automation Conference, Austin, TX

Modularity in gene transcription networks (invited talk)

Teaching Experience

2013 Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Teaching assistant for Introduction to Numerical Simulation, 1 semester (Luca Daniel)

2009–2010 Budapest University of Technology and Economics

Teaching assistant for Control Theory in Biology, 2 semesters (Levente Kovacs)

2006–2009 Budapest University of Technology and Economics

Teaching assistant for Signals and Systems I–II, 6 semesters (Tamas Barbarics)

Industry Experience

2008 **Dolphio Consulting Ltd., Hungary**

Summer intern, image processing applications (Zsolt Robotka)

Professional Service

2014-2015 Member of student council

Center for Integrative Synthetic Biology, Massachusetts Institute of Technology

2014 Organizer of invited session on "Context-dependence in biology"

IEEE Conference on Decision and Control

2012- Student member of IEEE

2010- Reviewer

IEEE Life Sciences Letters, Journal of the Royal Society Interface, Systems and Synthetic Biology, IEEE CDC, IEEE ACC

2009–2010 Co-supervisor of MSc projects in control theory

Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Hungary